Guide to the C. Matilda (Mortimer) Remington Papers, 1851-1871
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
C. Matilda (Mortimer) Remington Papers
1951-1971
Parsons, C. Matilda Mortimer Remington, 1842-1907
0.2 cubic feet (1 box)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
The collection contains correspondence between C. Matilda (Mortimer) Remington, her brother Benjamin Mortimer, her sister-in-law Sarah (Bates) Mortimer, and her mother. Also included are childhood drawings and sketches by Charlotte and a poem entitled "Reading" she wrote at age 13.
Biographical Note
Charlotte Matilda Mortimer (1842-1907) was born in New York to Eliza (Duyea) Mortimer and Benjamin Mortimer. She married banker Emory Brace Remington (1843-1875) in 1865 and had three children, Mortimer Remington (1868-1929), Charlotte Matilda Remington (1871-1880), and Emory Brace Remington (1874-1937). Emory passed away in 1875 and Matilda remarried to Charles Henry Parsons in 1891. Her granddaughter, Olive Remington (1897-1984), graduated from Vassar College in 1919.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains correspondence between C. Matilda (Mortimer) Remington, her brother Benjamin Mortimer, her sister-in-law Sarah (Bates) Mortimer, and her mother. The letters discuss topics including Remington's life in Brooklyn, her work as a schoolteacher, Benjamin and Sarah's travels in Australia, and the ongoing Civil War. Also included are childhood drawings and sketches by Remington and a poem entitled "Reading" she wrote at age 13.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Subjects:
Family--New York (State); Australia--Description and travel--Nineteenth century; United States—History—Civil War, 1861-1865
Document Types:
Correspondence; Drawings (visual works)
VCL Categories:
Family; War and War Crimes
Encoding Information
Encoded by Emma Gronbeck, March 2023.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Olive G. Malcolm (VC 1954).
Container List
- Drawings by C. Matilda (Mortimer) Remington, 1851 (Folder 1)
- Drawings by C. Matilda (Mortimer) Remington, 1852 (Folder 2)
- Drawings by C. Matilda (Mortimer) Remington, 1853 (Folder 3)
- Drawings by C. Matilda (Mortimer) Remington, undated (Folder 4)
- Letters from Benjamin Mortimer to C. Matilda (Mortimer) Remington, 1858-1859 (Folder 5)
- Letters from C. Matilda (Mortimer) Remington to Benjamin and Sarah Mortimer, 1855-1858 (Folder 6)
- Letters from C. Matilda (Mortimer) Remington to Benjamin and Sarah Mortimer, 1859-1860 (Folder 7)
- Letters from C. Matilda (Mortimer) Remington to Benjamin and Sarah Mortimer, 1861-1862 (Folder 8)
- Letters from C. Matilda (Mortimer) Remington to Benjamin and Sarah Mortimer, 1865-1869 (Folder 9)
- Letters from C. Matilda (Mortimer) Remington to Benjamin and Sarah Mortimer, 1870-1871 (Folder 10)
- Letters from C. Matilda (Mortimer) Remington to Benjamin and Sarah Mortimer, undated (Folder 11)
- Letters from C. Matilda (Mortimer) Remington to Benjamin and Sarah Mortimer, 1859-1871; [transcripts] (Folder 12)
- Letters from C. Matilda (Mortimer) Remington to her mother, 1858, 1869 (Folder 13)
- Poem: "Reading" by C. Matilda (Mortimer) Remington, 1855 (Folder 14)